A primitive embryo with an embryonic pole
which is an assimilative pole
and it will always, always enter the mucosa,
always through this pole.
Here I have drawn the uterine mucosa.
We can see here the embryo, really with those cells that are
information sensors.
Why? Because at this cell level here, there is a layer.
cells. So, this is called, what do we call this cavity?
Blastocoel. This layer here is called
what? The embryonic knob.
And then, right up front here, just here, what we will call the
cells, we're going to take a slightly Chinese name, it
will be called syncytiotrophoblast.
In situ, this means that there is a lytic activity, so
a sitting activity.
Either the mucosa is not ready, we do not want to welcome,
we are not ready.
Or, and this is very common, the embryo is not strong enough.
Because very often, in the early stages,
there are miscarriages that occur beforehand; there can be anomalies.
And very often at this level
it is the first miscarriages
is that the embryo is not strong enough
it will happen
it will give and so it is already this force there
if this force is not powerful
if the metabolism is not strong enough
if the animation
the soul
has not received this power
we will not be able to
enter the mucosa
and naturally it will be eliminated
and that is a syncytiotrophoblast
They will release here an acid, to the point that it will be an aggression for the mucosa.
This means that the mucosa that it has will, it's as if you pour acid,
there.
So the system, it can start to...
I must want to go into my nice warm nest.
First, we'll watch a little cartoon.
And there I would like you to observe what happens
because we will see it as a couple
and another film where we will see it
not as a couple but more in reality
and it is an important moment in your life
because it is almost a moment of incarnation
it is almost the moment when we want to incarnate well
because we enter the flesh
we enter the mucosa of the mother
we enter the...
we incarnate, we enter
really into the earth. Very early, we have what we call cell junctions
and these junctions
will depend on a substance we call calcium. That's why the
adhesive cells are called cadherins, which are calcium ions,
which give the strength
of cohesion. The moment we arrive in the mucosa...
of the uterus
the embryo has made its whole journey
we see there is a concentrated area
of concentrated cells
and in front of this concentrated cell area
we have a small layer of cells
that will change name
these will be called
the syncytiotrophoblast
which means we have a lytic activity
they will enter
release in fact completely
an acid
and make
entering into the mucosa, it is really an aggression, to the point that it causes micro-bleeding,
to the same point it creates a micro-scar in the uterus at the implantation site,
and to the same point that it can cause confusion about the dates of the last periods.
Sometimes the woman, she says, oh, look, I had, on the sixth day, she
says, look, I had some bleeding,
maybe that can lead to...
a confusion. What we observe is that we always enter through the assimilative pole
and in a very straight way. Never sideways, there is
no deviation, otherwise it risks
not entering. It enters because at that moment there is a metabolic field,
there is a very very powerful absorption that seeks the desire
to live. It's
really actually a search for life.
I accept life, I want to live.
I release my acid and I take my chance to enter
if I have enough power to succeed.
Thus, it is both a choice almost of the soul,
if you will, to incarnate.
So first, it enters well through the pole we call micro-mothers.
And now, we are going to look closely at this image.
You see, we can see what we call...
I see the cells we call the embryonic knob.
And we can see here the cells that are there, which we call the syncytiotrophoblast.
And the liquid flowing is the syncytiotrophoblast.
Which really comes to erode and enter the mucosa.
And in the mucosa here, we see it is rich.
It is swollen, it is rich in vessels, in arteries.
in small uterine glands, etc.
to welcome and allow nourishing the arriving zygote.
And look at what will happen.
First, he enters completely into the mucosa.
Secondly, at the moment he enters,
we see that there are all the cells around here.
Gentlemen,
look now at the embryo, we can see it is here. And what do you see?
We see
a small cavity appearing in the embryo. Look, walk
back. Thud, no cavity.
At the moment when I enter, hop,
a cavity appears here. You see? You see the small cavity
there.
it appears, I enter completely
and what else do we see, look
here
we can see really that there is a differentiation
between cells that are here
and cells that are there
that is to say that there are cells that are facing
the cavity that appears
and this small cavity
is called the cavity
of primitive amnion
and here we see cells
that surround this cavity
so the cells
that are facing the amniotic cavity
are the epithelial cells.
The cells that are facing
the blastocoel cavity
are the future
hypoblast cells.
In other words, that means they are
future endodermal type cells.
One looks at
the amniotic cavity
which is here.
Two, the others look at the cavity of the blastocoel.
These cells
here will later participate
in the formation
of another cavity
I will explain this
it will be a bit more difficult to understand
we will go a little deeper into this cavity
of amnion. For me, what is
important is that you imagine that at this moment
I already have
some cell differentiation
that appears. There are already cells
that are facing this cavity
and behind are cells that are facing
another cavity. And so what we must
reflect on is that I have two cavities
that appear, two layers of cells.
Everything that will be hypoblastic
will give rise to the future digestive system.
And everything that will be epiblastic
will give rise to the future neural system.
So,
let's look a bit at
the mechanism a bit more
subtle.
I’m hungry.
I need to eat.
So, I arrive. But we are still
in this process. Do not forget, what happens
already at this moment do you remember what we saw this morning I inform
myself I inform my friend who informs here my girlfriend who informs there, and everything, you see, and at the same time we saw
if I were to jump off the building there wouldn’t be more left
than the liquid of me on the ground.
Well imagine that here now the cell enters, I am the cell I enter here but
now I have a constraint, I enter
as if in butter, into this mucosa.
I enter there, I am going to release a bit of acid,
I will try to push,
I will lie down in there.
So the cells that are there,
at first, they receive a trophic signal,
no problem.
The cells that are behind here,
are still nourished by the amniotic cavity of the blastocoel,
no problem.
But the cells that are in the center,
they begin to be compressed,
deficient in nourishment,
They were already there, at the end, you see, at the membrane level.
And well, what happens?
All of a sudden we see the membrane cells appearing that
disappear.
You see?
And what remains?
It’s an exudate.
What will remain is a small cellular exudate that appears here.
And this cellular exudate...
It's the embryonic primitive amniotic cavity just forming.
But do not forget that there is always already a growth process.
What will this amniotic cavity become?
First, externally, it will eventually become what we call
the water bag.
Primitive amniotic cavity, see how it will evolve.
It will completely wrap around the embryo, completely surrounding it.
And all this is amniotic cavity.
And in the end, I swim in this cavity and
I am bathed and we will see that afterwards, it will grow differently because
there are cells that will engage in names, that will become amniotic cells, that will start to nourish, to
grow.
But another thing, what tissue do I have here? Epithelial cells.
You see? Look. Epithelial.
and here, hypoblastic
and the epithelial cells
what will they become?
the nervous system
and your nervous system
initially is a layer of cells
called the neural plate
and above, what do I have in the neural plate?
what kind of liquid?
amniotic fluid
that will be taken
in the closure
of my neural groove, which we will see tomorrow
in detail, or the day after tomorrow, I don’t remember,
so that it will completely
enclose a liquid inside
of your brain. And what will
this liquid be called?
The liquid will, I mean,
that comes, actually,
from the amniotic cavity. So, not only
inside
the depth of your being,
because, frankly, this cavity, it’s deep,
we forget that we have this
liquid inside us, you have your ventricular system and that you have this liquid
completely at the center of you, a little phylogeny like that,
completely at the center of you,
okay? It is already amniotic fluid. And completely outside
of you, what is it?
It’s amniotic fluid. And besides, when you have an embryo at this stage, what
do you do?
It’s amniotic fluid.
you drink liquid, you absorb liquid, you inform yourself
completely, why? Because
it’s a constellating liquid, it's a completely autocrine, paracrine liquid,
you totally inform yourself, you inform yourself of internal pressure, of pressure here, and
as chance would have it, we'll see later, that it's the integration of your coelom, thus
the closure of your peritoneal cavity, the
closure of your neural tube will occur at the same time. It’s synchronicities,
specific
inductions. It will all be done at the same time. Here, it is still a zygote. But the
fetus appears in relation to the primitive axial process, that is to say the establishment
of gastrulation.
There is a fetal form. This is a small zygote that she has.
The rest, we are in the lunar landscape,
of the woman, but with a soil rich in mucosa,
rich in glands, in nourishment.
And this is where we will make this moment, this choice where I can enter into my mucosa.
We see that he is trying to adhere, to enter, there he starts sending...
What do we say? Acid.
It’s a bit... You see?
There is a very important metabolic activity.
And now, we need to look here, everyone,
even gentlemen over there, look, look closely.
I am entering the mucosa.
Eighth day, amniotic cavity.
We see pressure appearing here on the right, pressure on the left.
And it is this that creates a pressure force
that is here.
It is here that this amniotic cavity will appear.
And it is here, when I have this embryonic knob, at the moment I have this cavity,
I have cells that organize and orient themselves.
towards my amniotic cavity
and cells that organize
and orient themselves towards my yolk sac
and it is here that I have the appearance
of a hypoblast and an epiblast
it is already there that I have a stage
of digestive type
and a digestive tissue
that is preparing and a tissue
of neurological type.